mywire.com 2008-12-17

# MyWire: Privacy Policy

## Overview

Your privacy is important, so MyWire has created this Privacy Policy to let you know what information we collect when you visit the MyWire web site (the "Site"), why we collect it, and how it is used. The terms "you," "your" and "yours" refer to all visitors of our Site. The terms "MyWire", "we", "us" and "our" refer to MyWire and its subsidiaries and affiliates. This Privacy Policy is governed by our Terms of Use. By accessing this Site and the content, information, products and services available on this Site (collectively the "Services"), you consent to the data practices described in this Privacy Policy and other terms in our Terms of Use. We may periodically make changes to this Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy frequently and remain informed about any changes, so we encourage you to visit this page often. 

## Index

  1. Information We Collect; How We Collect It
  2. Is Information Shared or Disclosed?
  3. Some Examples of When We Share Your Information
  4. How to Stop Sharing of Information
  5. Correcting Information
  6. Security and Passwords
  7. Emails Sent to You
  8. Emails Sent to Others
  9. Cookies
  10. International Transfers
  11. Children/Minors
  12. Contacting MyWire

### 1\. Information We Collect; How We Collect It

We may request at times that you voluntarily supply us with personal information. Such personal information includes any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, home or other physical address, an email address, phone number, other contact information, whether at work or at home, and credit card information. Generally some or all of this information is requested when you register on the Site or when you provide information in connection with an online transaction.

MyWire, its service providers and all vendors providing products or services through our Site use your personal information to, among other things: operate the Site and/or undertake to perform your transactions; create and share reports about your transactions among themselves; perform credit fraud screening services for transactions between you and MyWire and/or others; and market or promote other products or services of interest to you.

MyWire also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookie information and the pages you request. We intend to continue improving the content and function of our Site, and we monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help MyWire provide content of interest to you, add and improve features of our Services and enhance the design and layout of our Site.

If you participate in MyWire's SmartMatch program, you will be required to provide certain additional information, including your social security or tax I.D. number and a bank account routing number. This information will enable MyWire to make any required tax filings resulting from any payments made to you as a participant in the SmartMatch program, as well as facilitate the payment of any amounts earned by you under this program. This information will be collected at the time that a participant registers for the program; and no participant may register without first providing this information.

### 2\. Is Information Shared or Disclosed?

MyWire may store and disclose personal information as allowed or required by applicable law, including making disclosures that are necessary or advisable to: 

  * protect the rights, safety or property of users of our Site, the public, MyWire or our suppliers; and
  * conform to legal or regulatory requirements.

Under certain circumstances, MyWire may choose to trade, sell or rent your personal information with trustworthy third parties. Also, if MyWire should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, we may sell the information you provide to MyWire on this Site to a third party or share your personal information with any company with whom we merge. Users who would rather not provide any of the information requested by our registration process do not need to register with MyWire. You can still view some of the content available on our Site without registering. You will, however, need to establish a password-protected personal account to access most of the information available on our Site and to use any Services, such as storing information of interest to you and managing your magazine subscriptions.

Except under extraordinary circumstances (for instance involving MyWire's bankruptcy or its merger with or acquisition by another Company), MyWire will not share certain highly sensitive information collected in the SmartMatch registration process (specifically your social security or tax I.D. number and bank routing information) with any third party.

### 3\. Some Examples of When We Share Your Information

We work with many publishers and their agents to provide you with access to the content available on this Site and to facilitate your purchase of certain products and services. Accordingly, certain items and content sold on the Site are delivered to you by companies other than MyWire. This includes magazines and other items sent through the mail. It also includes digital items you order on the Site but which you receive directly from third parties. In the cases where you purchase an item on our Site that is fulfilled by another company, you become a customer of the publisher or seller of that item, and we will provide certain of your personal information to that third party. We typically provide personal information such as the item purchased, the price you paid, your name, your email address and your mailing address. We may also ask you to provide us with certain marketing or demographic information at the time of your purchase. If you choose to provide us with any such marketing or demographic information, we may be contractually obligated to share this information with the applicable third party. We generally have no control over how the third party will use your personal information, which might include sending you renewal notices when a magazine subscription is near expiration, direct marketing of other publications from the same company, or the marketing of your name and address to other companies for the purpose of marketing other publications or other products and services to you.

Once you have subscribed to a magazine or other item for sale on our Site, we use the fulfillment agent selected by the applicable publisher to fulfill the processing and shipping to you of your subscription or other purchase. This requires us to provide the appropriate publisher’s fulfillment agent with certain of your personal information, which typically includes your name and shipping address. In some cases, we will also provide a fulfillment agent with your billing information so that they may process the actual billing for your subscription or other purchase; however, we will provide such information to the publishers’ fulfillment companies and agents only through encrypted links.

We have marketing partnerships with certain publishers and other partners which enable you to come to our Site from a hyperlink located on such partners’ web sites and access certain Services. If, in the course of such a visit to our Site, you sign up for your personal MyWire account, then we are contractually obligated to share your name and email address with the applicable partner. We may also ask you to provide us with certain marketing or demographic information at the time of your registration. If you choose to provide us with any such marketing or demographic information, we may be contractually obligated to share this information with the applicable partner.

In any case, we will not be liable for any damages that may result from the use or misuse of your personal information by third parties from which you purchase subscriptions or other items through the Services, by any fulfillment agent that may process your transaction, or by third parties with whom we have marketing and other partnerships.

### 4\. How to Stop Sharing of Information

You can let us know that you do not wish to receive information about new features and special offers by opting out on the My Account page, which is accessible from our home page. You will not be able to opt out of MyWire sharing certain of your personal information with the publisher of any magazine or other periodical that you purchase on the Site. To cancel your MyWire account, visit the My Account Page, and select edit my membership. Follow the prompts for cancellation. If you have difficulty, contact Customer Support to initiate the account cancellation process.

### 5\. Correcting Information

To update your personal information, simply sign in and go to My Account from our home page. You can make changes to your account information at any time. To protect your privacy and security, we will also verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. You may also contact Customer Support to communicate any questions or concerns.

### 6\. Security and Passwords

The personally identifiable information we collect about you is stored in limited access servers. MyWire intends to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect such information from unauthorized access or disclosure. While we make efforts to ensure that your information is secure on our system, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

When your password or credit card number is requested on this Site, we use secure socket layer (SSL) encryption to present secure pages to protect that information. You can tell if you are using a secure server by looking at the bottom of your browser window. In Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer, you will see a lock icon. When the symbol is unbroken or the padlock appears to be in its closed state, the page is encrypted and therefore secure. If you wish to take advantage of the latest encryption standards, be sure you have the latest version of the browser you use. You can download the latest version from the Netscape or Microsoft web sites. Using beta versions of browsers is not recommended.

You can review or change your MyWire Subscription or credit card information by signing in and accessing the My Account area of the Site. You can also change your password at any time, and you can set a new password in case you forgot your old one, by going to My Account, which is accessible from our home page. Please keep your password in a safe place and do not to divulge it to anyone. Also remember to sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit. This is especially important if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place such as a library or Internet cafe.

Your account is protected by your password. You choose a password when you first start an account with us. Your password needs to: 

  * be between 8 and 20 characters long
  * include both numbers and letters
  * not contain symbols (*, $, #, %, etc.)

Make sure to select a password that is not obvious. A good password includes seemingly random letters and numbers, for example, F3M8N1GR.

### 7\. Emails Sent to You

We optionally send you emails relating to certain activities in your account, including order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices and credit card problem notices.

We will send you email notices about new features, products and services available on MyWire from time to time. You can subscribe or unsubscribe to this notification service by going to My Account, which is accessible from our home page. You can also unsubscribe to this notification service by following the ‘Manage your Email Settings’ link located near the bottom of the email message you receive from us.

We may send you email notices based on purchases you have made on our Site. For instance, we may send an email letting you know when a magazine subscription you purchased through us is expiring. You can tell us not to send you these emails by opting out at the time of the purchase.

If you subscribe to any of our email newsletters or our notification service, we will use your personal information to send these email newsletters or notifications to you. You can change how you receive the email newsletters you sign up for, or request to stop receiving them, by going to My Account. You can also request to stop receiving any email newsletter by following the ‘Manage your Email Settings’ link located near the bottom of each newsletter.

We may send you email notices regarding Site and service announcements containing important information about the Services including but not limited to, confirmation notices and status information about your purchases or subscriptions. You will not be able to un-subscribe from these service announcements.

### 8\. Emails Sent to Others

If you use our email feature to email an article to a friend, we will email the individuals you select and invite them to come to MyWire to view the item of information you selected to share with them. If they do not have an account with MyWire, we will offer them an opportunity to open an account and accept the terms and conditions of our Services. We will give each of your friends the option to choose whether or not they wish to receive further emails from MyWire.

### 9\. Cookies

Cookies are pieces of information that your browser receives from web sites and stores on your computer's hard drive. MyWire uses cookies to improve our Site and make it easier to use. Cookies permit MyWire to recognize users and avoid repetitive requests for the same information. MyWire (or a third-party provider we contract with) may occasionally include specific tags (also known as "clear gifs" or "web beacons") on selected web pages or email messages to customers. The tags provide statistical information to MyWire so we can better understand what communications are successful. The tags may indicate which email addresses responded to a particular email, but the statistics gathered are only used in aggregate.

### 10\. International Transfers

Personal information collected on this Site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which MyWire or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this Site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

### 11\. Children/Minors

This Site is not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 18. MyWire does not sell products for purchase by children. Any person who provides their information to MyWire through the registration page for new users or any other part of the Site represents to MyWire that they are 18 years of age or older.

### 12\. Contacting MyWire

Our goal is to respect your privacy. If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at [privacy@mywire.com](mailto:privacy@mywire.com?ai=542&ci=491&ri=2881). MyWire welcomes your comments and questions.

Last updated on April 15th, 2007.  
Copyright 2007 MyWire. All rights reserved.
